Sri Krishna Chaitanya N

Senior Software Engineer with 8.6 years of experience on .Net

Vijayawada, Andhra Pradesh srikrishnachaitanyan9_wvf@indeedemail.com 8106545635

To be a part of the challenging team which strives for the better growth of the organization and which explores my potential and provides me with the opportunity to enhance my talent with an intention to be an asset to the company.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

FreeLancer

February 2017 to November 2017

Senior Software Engineer

Senior Software Engineer

FreeLancer - Hyderabad, Telangana February 2017 to November 2017

Position Senior Software Engineer

Client Agadia, US

The Project

PAHub is web-based software that simplifies and automates the end-to-end prior authorization process. This Application is used by most of the Health insurance Agencies in US. It offers effective workflow and document management capabilities which provide the perfect solution for managing prior authorization requests and is designed to maximize the benefits of prior authorization for use in.

Responsibilities

- Enhancing the application based on the client requirements.
- Check the functionality based on the FRDs, whether everything is included or not.
- Doing multiple rounds of testing to verify the modified functionality.
- Using Asp.net Ajax controls for the better performance in the application.

Languages Asp.Net, C#, Ado.net, Web Api, Umbraco 7 Special Software Visual Studio 2010, Sql Server 2008, Team Foundation Server Work Location Hyderabad, India

Senior Software Engineer

Dell International November 2016 to December 2016

Employer Dell International Services Title FCC Period Nov 2016 to Dec 2016 Position Senior Software Engineer Client Dell International Services

The Project

Freight cost calculation application comes in picture upon Manifest closure. This application calculates the initial Freight cost. This project is to facilitate the delivery of enhancements to the current Freight Cost Calculation (FCC) functionality. The project will facilitate of country specific VAT calculations and provide greater reporting capabilities.

Responsibilities

- Using Agile Scrum methodology.
- Interacting with the client daily to get the requirements.
- Using JavaScript for client side validations.
- Using Asp.net Ajax controls.
- Enhancing the application based on client requirements.

Languages Asp.Net, C#, Entity Framework, Mvc, Web Api, Angular 4 Special Software Visual Studio 2010, Sql Server 2008, Team Foundation Server Work Location Hyderabad, India

Senior Software Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services February 2016 to September 2016

Employer Tata Consultancy Services
Title TRANSRISK
Period Feb 2016 to Sep 2016
Position Senior Software Engineer
Client Wilmar International Limited, Singapore
The Project

TransRisk, a web-based market risk management solution provides manufacturing, processing and trading companies with a robust, customizable and stable commodity and currency risk management solution. Based on Risk framework, a widely accepted global standard for measuring and decomposing risk, TransRisk, a decision-enabling Business Intelligence tool helps measure and manages risk. It calculates net exposures based on the business process and allows users to have single accurate, view of exposures, mark-to-market P&L and risk across the organization, thereby bettering the synchronization of business strategies.

Responsibilities

- Using Agile Scrum methodology.
- Interacting with the client daily to get the requirements.
- Using JavaScript for client side validations.
- Using Asp.net Ajax controls.
- Enhancing the application based on client requirements.

Languages Asp.Net, C#.Net , Ado.net, WCF, React JS 14.7 Special Software Visual Studio 2010, Sql Server 2008, Team Foundation Server Work Location Hyderabad, India

Senior Software Engineer

Transgraph Consulting Pvt Ltd

April 2014 to July 2014

Employer Transgraph Consulting Pvt Ltd Title nPHASE Period April 2014 to July 2014 Position Senior Software Engineer Client Verizon The Project

Single Interface to the M2M World nPhase is wholly owned by Verizon, providing advanced Machine to Machine (M2M) services to the world's leading wireless operators such as Verizon and Vodafone, and enterprise customers with the most demanding needs for data reliability, coverage, security and innovation in M2M. Industies served include transportation/construction, utilities, healthcare, retail industrial, financial services, consumer electronics and government. nPhase leverages the global leadership in advanced connectivity technologies provided by Qualcomm, the industry leading network and channel provided by Verizon Wireless, and over ten years of experience as an M2M pioneer to lead the advancement of M2M.

Responsibilities

- Enhancing the application based on client requirements.
- Fixing the issues and releasing the code on regular basis.

Languages Asp.Net, C#.Net , Ado.net, WCF Work Location Hyderabad, India

Senior Software Engineer

Marlabs Software Pvt Ltd July 2012 to August 2013

Senior Software Engineer

Relational Security Corporation - Mysore, Karnataka July 2012 to 2013

US

The Project

Rsam offers the most intuitive and flexible solutions to successfully manage an organization's unique risk, compliance and security needs quickly. Rsam technology automates processes and transforms data into intelligence, allowing organizations to minimize risk exposure, maintain compliance and gain efficiencies that optimize business performance and decreases the overall cost of compliance.

Rsam allows you to automate and manage governance, risk and compliance processes across the entire enterprise, Leverage Rsam GRC to create a central risk repository delivering unparallel visibility, intelligence, and control of your organizations risk and compliance posture. Modular solutions allow for a phased approach to building GRC programs quickly and sustain them with fewer resources and without the need for costly professional services.

Responsibilities

- Worked on Manage module.
- Used Infragistics web controls.
- Used JavaScript for client side validations.
- Used Agile Scrum methodology for the implementation.

• Providing solutions to Relational Security Corporation by enhancing application according to their requirement.

Languages Asp.Net, Vb.Net , Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2010, Sql Server 2008, Visual Source Safe Work Location Mysore, India

Senior Software Engineer

Inteq Software Pvt Ltd August 2010 to January 2012

Employer Inteq Software
Title EZ-NET
Period August 2010 to January 2012
Position Senior Software Engineer
Client MZI Health Care, US
The Project

EZ-NET is a secured web based application for exchanging information between physicians, health plans, independent physician associations (IPAs), managed care organizations (MCOs), and management service organizations.

EZ-NET's secure nature enables your organization to make important data accessible to your business providers via the internet or intranet, without compromising EZ-NET system security.

Responsibilities

- Worked on Employee and Client modules.
- Implemented Agile Scrum methodology.
- Worked on Infragistics controls for the implementation.
- Interacting with the client about the requirements.
- Resolving problems faced by MZI People on their daily Usage.

Languages Asp.Net, Vb.Net , Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2008, Sql Server 2008, Visual Source Safe Work Location Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer

Promatrix Solutions - Hyderabad, Telangana December 2008 to May 2010

Client Noble Grossart Ltd, UK

The Project

Globus is a back office HTTP solution used for producing customer invoices and sales commissions. Clients and Employees timesheets are maintained through this Globus system. Commissions for recruiters and salespeople are generated and individual commission statements are available to the employees through Globus.

This system maintains all the details of beneficiary types, pay periods, commission schedules, bill pay units and invoice cycles. It also maintains all the information about the employees who are working currently and also the people who worked for the company.

Globus also maintains the information about the employee client relationship like which employee is working for which client. Employee will enter the time for which he worked in hour's format. The invoice manager checks the time sheet and generates invoice for that period.

Responsibilities

- Worked on Waterfall methodology in implementing the application.
- Used Asp.net validation controls for validating the pages.
- Worked on Sql Server stored procedures and views.
- Used Normalization in creating the table structures.
- Maintaining the application properly by rectifying the problems and introducing new things regularly based on the requirement.

Languages Asp.Net, C# , Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2008, Sql Server 2005, Visual Source Safe Work Location Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer

Promatrix Solutions April 2007 to May 2010

Software Engineer

Promatrix Solutions - Hyderabad, Telangana March 2008 to November 2008

Client Technofin Solutions, New Delhi

The Project

TechBuild's ambition is to integrate all departments and functions across a company on to a single computer system that can serve all those different department's particular needs. TechBuild combines all departments together into a single integrated software program that runs off a single database, so that the various departments can more easily share information and communicate with each other.

This project mainly focuses on user resume database and requirements stored by the Business developer and employer. This project maintains process chain between business developer, manager and recruiter.

Responsibilities

- Worked on creating tables, views and stored procedures.
- Used normalized database for the effective usage.
- Used JavaScript for client side validations.
- Involved in client meetings.
- Providing programming support in development of web pages, using .net for implementing the proposed system.

Languages Asp.Net, C#, Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2008, Sql Server 2005, Visual Source Safe Work Location Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer

Promatrix Solutions - Hyderabad, Telangana May 2007 to February 2008 Client Technofin Solutions, New Delhi

The Project

Automate is a web application designed by keeping in view of the various customer invoices that are maintained at automobile service center. An automobile center which deals with hundreds of vehicles daily where in people need a system which quickly provides services which could enhance the day to day activities of the service center with efficiency and correctness.

Automate is a user friendly GUI application that will automate different activities involved in the day to day activities of QSC (Quick Service Center). The system will help in reducing the time and effort in preparation of quotation invoices and reports. It provides a error free generation all the reports to provide security to the different users of the system.

Responsibilities

- Worked on Waterfall methodology in implementing the project.
- Worked on Asp.net controls and JavaScript for validations.
- Worked on fixing Client issues by interacting with them.
- Providing programming support in development of web pages using Asp.Net.

Languages Asp.Net, Vb.Net , Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2005, Sql Server 2005, Visual Source Safe Work Location Hyderabad, India

Asst. Software Engineer

Sai People Solutions Pvt Ltd April 2006 to April 2007

Application Areas

- Has a Total Experience of 8.6 Years in Software Development on .Net Technologies
- Worked on Frameworks 3.5, 3.0, 2.0
- Worked on Asp.Net, C#, Vb.Net and Sql Server
- Has worked on Visual Studio 2010, Visual Studio 2008 and Visual Studio 2005
- Has worked on Sql Server 2008, Sql Server 2005, Sql Server 2000
- Hands on experience on Ajax Controls, Infragistics controls
- Experience on javascript and Angular 4, React JS 14.7
- Experience on using Web Services, Ado.net, MVC
- Experience on Web API, WCF, Umbraco 7

Employer Sai People Solutions
Title SAINEX
Period April 2006 to April 2007
Position Asst. Software Engineer
Client Sai People Solutions, US

The Project

Sainex is intended to provide an integral application for its operations for Sai People Solutions. Sai People Solutions is providing consulting for various software companies. The Account Manager of Sai People Solutions in Us interacts with their clients and come to know the requirement and the desired candidates required to them. Client provides essential information like Job Title, No of openings, Type of Job, essential and necessary candidate requirements. Then the Account Manager creates a position in Sainex.

The employees designated at various levels select and interact with the prospective candidates for a particular position and enter the results into the system. Bill rate paid to Sai People Solutions by the client upon successful completion of the opening. Sai People Solutions pays to the candidate the agreed salary which is called as Pay Rate. The difference in two is called as Spread, which is the profit to Sai People Solutions.

Responsibilities

- Worked on Employee, Client and Employee Client Maintenance modules.
- Worked on Waterfall methodology in implementing.
- Used JavaScript for client side validations.
- Involved in client meetings to gather the requirements and getting input about the issues.
- Resolving problems faced by users on their daily

Usage and providing solutions for them by enhancing the application according to their requirement.

Languages Asp.Net, C#, Ado.net Special Software Visual Studio 2005, Sql Server 2000, Source Offsite Work Location Hyderabad, India

Education

Msc IS in Information Systems

Andhra University 2005

BCA in Bachelor of Computer Applications

Acharya Nagarjuna University 2002

Skills / IT Skills

• Languages: Asp.net, C#, Vb.net, Ado.net

Frameworks: .Net Framework 3.5, 3.0, 2.0, Mvc 4

Tools: VisualStudio2010, VisualStudio2008, Visual Studio 2005

Databases: SQL Server 2008/2005/2000

Web Servers: IIS 6.0/5.0

Web Technologies: Html, Ajax, Xml, JQuery

Scripting Languages: JavaScript, Angular 4, React JS 14.7